<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Modem &amp; Reboot</title>
    <link>https://signumfraud.pages.dev/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Modem &amp; Reboot</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 00:56:17 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://signumfraud.pages.dev/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Next Steps</title>
      <link>https://signumfraud.pages.dev/next-steps/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 00:56:17 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://signumfraud.pages.dev/next-steps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello again, dears.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week, I finished &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.freecodecamp.org/&#34;&gt;FreeCodeCamp&lt;/a&gt; Responsive Web Design course&amp;rsquo;s first section and built a simple survey as a certification project. No &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/CSS&#34;&gt;CSS&lt;/a&gt; code demanded, so I didn&amp;rsquo;t bother with it, just completed the form in &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/HTML&#34;&gt;HTML&lt;/a&gt; and earned my first certificate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honestly, because of curriculum I was hoping a little more complicated certificate project. I can understand there&amp;rsquo;s not much quirky things with plain HTML, some basic understanding about tags and attributes solves the most of entry-level problems but maybe they can demand a little more challenging things, especially some CSS knowledge would be nice (the only thing they demands linking a css file to html file) and lessons already contains nice amount of information about basic CSS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next sections, as far as I understand, more CSS oriented. Starts with &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Learn/CSS/Building_blocks/The_box_model&#34;&gt;box model&lt;/a&gt; and more about with &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/CSS/CSS_flexible_box_layout/Basic_concepts_of_flexbox&#34;&gt;Flexbox&lt;/a&gt; and typography. Maybe this is why first section ends with an HTML only project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am aware, I am a little bit more slow nowadays. Frankly, this isn&amp;rsquo;t about the course or curriculum but about my daily life. I was more lazy and found interesting excuses for not working on my learning the programming journey, unsurprisingly. But this is not means everything is bleak, also I made some reasonable things too. For example, found out &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theodinproject.com/&#34;&gt;The Odin Project&lt;/a&gt; and decided to use it together with FreeCodeCamp. Worked a little bit more on &lt;a href=&#34;https://git-scm.com/&#34;&gt;git&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/&#34;&gt;github&lt;/a&gt;, at least now I can handle this blog&amp;rsquo;s simple tasks from command-line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Weekend was uneventful, I watched second season of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.imdb.com/title/tt1869454/&#34;&gt;Good Omens&lt;/a&gt;. Ordered a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Light_therapy&#34;&gt;light therapy&lt;/a&gt; lamp (or &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Light_box&#34;&gt;lightbox&lt;/a&gt;?).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After sending this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll start reading &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dune_(novel)&#34;&gt;Dune&lt;/a&gt;, which I was delaying for years. Wish me luck!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for reading!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Another Day</title>
      <link>https://signumfraud.pages.dev/another-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 02:28:42 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://signumfraud.pages.dev/another-day/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello, again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I finished third chapter of &lt;a href=&#34;https://freecodecamp.org/&#34;&gt;FreeCodeCamp&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s web design course. It was solely about colours and honestly was a bit boring but an easy achievement, anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And yes, I changed my &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;hugo&lt;/a&gt; theme &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/joeroe/risotto&#34;&gt;risotto&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/LukasJoswiak/etch&#34;&gt;etch&lt;/a&gt;. This one is more minimal and easy-to-read, at least for me and my eyes. Besides technically less moving parts; no &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/JavaScript&#34;&gt;JavaScript&lt;/a&gt;, no &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Learn/CSS/Styling_text/Web_fonts&#34;&gt;web fonts&lt;/a&gt; and icons, etc. I lost personal information area which was in right panel but not a problem, I added a contact page specially for these information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Weekend was good, I rested and slept more than plenty. Cleaned and re-organanized my room. I made a big box of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Electronic_waste&#34;&gt;e-waste&lt;/a&gt;; three old and unfunctional mobile computers, too many ram modules from different dimensions and eras, tangled cable colonies, old speakers and headphones, a cocktail of a dozen harddrives, cd and dvd drives, a wireless mouse, more cables, etc. All hoard will go to an &lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;NGO&lt;/a&gt; for recycling and they&amp;rsquo;ll use the income for education.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again last weekend, played &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.minecraft.net/en-us&#34;&gt;Minecraft&lt;/a&gt; for the first time ever. Of course I heard it and watched some crazy videos. But until &lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/&#34;&gt;Google Play&lt;/a&gt; gifted it&amp;rsquo;s mobile version with my new &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/chromebook/&#34;&gt;Chromebook&lt;/a&gt; never tried before. It is a good sandbox game but maybe too grindy for me (yes, a guy shoved thousands of hours to online games wrote this sentence).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, I poked &lt;a href=&#34;https://git-scm.com/&#34;&gt;git&lt;/a&gt; a little. It&amp;rsquo;s complicated if I understand right. I just read a few page from &lt;a href=&#34;https://git-scm.com/book/en/v2&#34;&gt;Pro Git Book&lt;/a&gt; but maybe I should look for easier entryways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for reading!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Edit:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Somehow, I managed to use git after an hour and deployed this site via Github to Cloudflare! Hehe, cya all for now.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Second Day</title>
      <link>https://signumfraud.pages.dev/second-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 21:25:11 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://signumfraud.pages.dev/second-day/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I finished second section of &lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;FreeCodeCamp&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s Responsive Web Design course and the task was building a cafe menu. I learnt about &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;style&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; tag, referring &lt;code&gt;.css&lt;/code&gt; files from &lt;code&gt;.html&lt;/code&gt;, comments, selectors (id, class, etc.), font properties and text formatting, margins and padding and something more I didn&amp;rsquo;t remember at the moment. I think this is a productive day, I hope I can keep this tempo in the upcoming days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also today I learned about &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.markdownguide.org/&#34;&gt;markdown&lt;/a&gt; a bit, obviously because of &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;hugo&lt;/a&gt; and updated my first post and about page, added links.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s all folks, thank you for reading!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World</title>
      <link>https://signumfraud.pages.dev/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 14:46:12 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://signumfraud.pages.dev/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As an aspiring programmer, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t think of more cliche expression other than &amp;ldquo;hello world&amp;rdquo; for a title of first post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am not a CS student, neither an engineer nor working on tech related job. Somehow I got the idea that computing and programming were fun things. So, I made some research and nowadays trying to learn basics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just finished first section of &lt;a href=&#34;https://freecodecamp.org/&#34;&gt;FreeCodeCamp&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s Responsive Web Design course. I think I know a few things about HTML now and I&amp;rsquo;ll start next section after completed my drudgery with this website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope my English is a little better than my programming skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for reading!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
